Guide to the Randolph Linsly Simpson African-American Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Series I. Visual Material
  - PHOTOGRAPHIC POSTCARDS
    - Unknown photographer "Totein' de Wash, Pine Bluff, NC" Woman stands outdoors; large bundle of laundry on head. Photographic postcard, circa 1910 (Box 27, Folder 1051)
      Item #1598
    - Sandy's Studio, no location Full length formal portrait; lady seated, wearing white dress, cloak and hat. Photographic postcard, circa 1925 (Box 27)
      Item #1599
    - Unknown photographer "Carne Frita." Old man stands in slippers on park walk holding a small flask and walking stick. Photographic postcard, 1931 (Box 27)
      In pencil verso, "a mi querido pariente Rafaelito -- Alfonso Carnefrita."
      Item #1600
    - Unknown photographer "Aunt Rhoda 100 Years Old"; aged woman sitting in doorway, cat beside her. Photographic postcard, circa 1925 (Box 27)
      Item #1601
    - L.L.Cook Co., Milwaukee "B-202 Uncle 'Doug' Ambrose, Internationally Famous Civil War Slave at Lewis Turpentine Still and Plantation, Brooksville, Florida;" Old man with cane seated on plank ramp. Photographic postcard, circa 1925 (Box 27)
      See also: 1539, 1552, 1579, 1585.
      Item #1602
    - Unknown photographer Seven young boys in school uniforms and overcoats, seated with hats in lap. Photographic postcard, circa 1906 (Box 27)
      Dated from postmark, Berwyn, PA.
      Item #1603
    - A.J. Kingsbury, Antigo, WI "At Rest, X 8:" man lies as though asleep in the weeds. Photographic postcard, circa 1920 (Box 27)
      Item #1604
    - Unknown photographer Full length formal portrait, two ladies sitting in wicker chair set of Coney Island Boardwalk. Photographic postcard, circa 1930 (Box 27)
      Item #1605
    - Unknown photographer Half length portrait of man in suit; elaborate decorative border. Photographic postcard, circa 1930 (Box 27)
      Item #1606
    - Unknown photographer Full length formal portrait of young couple, she in a plaid skirt, sitting on brick wall set; he stands behind; many flowers. Photographic postcard, circa 1932 (Box 27)
      Item #1607
    - Metcalfe, Palm Beach Couple in wicker rolling chair, black attendant. Photographic postcard, circa 1910 (Box 27)
      Item #1608
    - Unknown photographer Full length portrait, lady standing in front of canvas backdrop holding white dove. Photographic postcard, circa 1905 (Box 27)
      Item #1609
    - Unknown photographer Three quarter length formal portrait, young lady seated, facing left. Photographic postcard, circa 1921 (Box 27)
      Item #1610
    - Unknown photographer Full length formal portrait; woman seated with book on lap. Photographic postcard, circa 1921 (Box 27)
      Item #1611
    - Smith Studio, Martinsburg, WV Full length informal portrait, young woman in lace dress stands beside institutional building holding pennant for "Storer" [College]. Photographic postcard, circa 1905 (Box 27)
      Item #1612
    - "Picturegoer" Series, London "Paul Robeson, London Films" publicity still, headshot of Robeson. Photographic postcard, circa 1939 (Box 27)
      Item #1613
    - Meriden Gravure Co., Meriden, CT Augusta Savage's "The Harp" at World's Fair 1940, New York (Box 27)
      Item #1614
    - Unknown photographer Two traction car conductors: one on, second beside car No. 30. Photographic postcard, circa 1913 (Box 27)
      Item #1615
    - Schumacher, Los Angeles The Rotograph Co., New York City "Rotograph" Series. B 701 Booker T. Washington;" three quarter length portrait of Washington seated in renaissance revival chair, legs crossed. Photographic postcard, circa 1910 (Box 27)
      Item #1616
    - Unknown photographer The Red Skelton Radio Show cast and principals, including "The Four Knights." Photographic postcard, 1948 (Box 27)
      Item #1617
    - Unknown photographer "The Original 'I-Got-Em', St. Petersburg, Fla." Man in formal dress with top hat, apron and holding a basket in each hand; stands between palmetto trees. Photographic postcard, circa 1910 (Box 27, Folder 1052)
      Item #1618
    - Unknown photographer Half length portrait: seven men in white tie, depicted in two rows. Photographic postcard, 1920s (Box 27)
      Item #1619
    - Unknown photographer "Four Flash Devils", four men sing and dance in tandem on stage. Photographic postcard, 1920s (Box 27)
      In pencil, verso, "Cotton Club."
      Item #1620
    - Unknown photographer Young woman in shorts sits on set of Sloppy Joe's Bar. Photographic postcard, circa 1925 (Box 27)
      Item #1621
    - Unknown Italian photographer "Mr. Paul Robeson, Mr. Henry Wilcoxson, Mr. Wallace Ford at the Pyramids near Cairo Egypt, during the production of Jericho, circa 1930 (Box 27)
      Item #1622
    - Unknown photographer Group photo of early "Our Gang:" Photographic postcard, 1920s (Box 27)
      Item #1623
    - Unknown photographer Four small children seated on and before stonewall in front of house. Photographic postcard, circa 1910 (Box 27)
      Item #1624
    - Unknown photographer "'Using yo' head,' Lewis Plantation, Brooksville, Florida;" woman, foreground, balances basket of wash on her head; background, children sit on shanty porch. Photographic postcard, circa 1915 (Box 27)
      Item #1625
    - Unknown photographer Mr. Jack Richmond stands outdoors with hound, shotgun powder horn over shoulder. Photographic postcard, circa 1910 (Box 27)
      Item #1626
    - Unknown photographer Family group outdoors in field. Photographic postcard, circa 1925 (Box 27)
      Item #1627
    - Penn Studio, Baltimore, MD Full length formal portrait; man in white band uniform stands holding baton. Photographic postcard, circa 1930 (Box 27)
      Item #1628
    - Unknown photographer Oval group photo of Edward, Douglass, Archie, and Mr Ernest Jordan. Photographic postcard, circa 1910 (Box 27)
      All identified in pencil, verso.
      Item #1629
    - A.L. Macbeth, Baltimore, MD Full length group portrait, three men in suits, overcoats and hats; cigarettes dangle from fingers of man at left and center. Photographic postcard, circa 1920 (Box 27)
      Item #1630
    - Unknown photographer Group portrait: four men in formal attire. Photographic postcard, circa 1910 (Box 27)
      Item #1631
    - Unknown photographer Two girls, seated, in white dresses and white knee socks, one wears hat. Photographic postcard, circa 1915 (Box 27)
      Item #1632
    - Echte Foto "Lord Kitchener: Melodisc Records:" Man in suit and felt hat stands at microphone. Photographic postcard, circa 1940 (Box 27)
      Item #1633
    - James K... Radio Cit... [off edge] "The Colmans:" publicity still of family performing group. Photographic postcard, circa 1940 (Box 27)
      Item #1634
    - Uitg. Takken, Utrecht "Sarah Vaughan:" head and shoulders with autograph in negative. Photographic postcard, circa 1940 (Box 27)
      Item #1635
    - Universum-Film Aktiengesellschaft, Berlin-Tempelhof "Harry Belafonte" publicity still of Belafonte seated with guitar in lap. Photographic postcard, circa 1940 (Box 27)
      Item #1636
    - J. Begales & Co., E.C. Printers & Publishers, Guaranteed Real Photograph "Photo by Sport & General" "Sam Langford" boxer strikes pose; cadets stand behind fence in deep background. Photographic postcard, circa 1910 (Box 27)
      Item #1637
    - Amtliche Olympia-Postkarte, Reichsportverlag, Berlin Williams (U.S.A.) leaving the blocks, 1936 Olympic Games, Berlin. Photographic postcard (Box 27)
      Item #1638
    - Unknown photographer Satchell Paige in Cincinnati uniform demonstrates technique. Photographic postcard, circa 1939 (Box 27)
      In ink, verso, "Best Wishes, Satchell Paige."
      Item #1639
    - Unknown photographer Al Smith in batting stance. Photographic postcard, circa 1939 (Box 27, Folder 1053)
      Autograph, recto, in ink, across image.
      Item #1640
    - Unknown photographer Tombstone of John Brown, his father and his son Oliver. Photographic postcard, circa 1905 (Box 27)
      Item #1641
    - Unknown photographer Plaque at John Brown's grave, noting the event at Harper's Ferry. Photographic postcard, circa 1905 (Box 27)
      Item #1642
    - Takken, Germany "The Platters:" three quarter length portrait. Photographic postcard, circa 1950 (Box 27)
      Item #1643
    - Unknown photographer Full length portrait of "Blanche Calloway;" autograph in negative. Photographic postcard, circa 1934 (Box 27)
      Item #1644
    - Whelan, Long Beach, CA "Nat King Cole, 1959"; half length of Cole on tarmac beside plane. Photographic postcard (Box 27)
      Item #1645
    - Whelan, Long Beach, CA Lionel Hampton and band deplaning from Pan Am. Photographic postcard, 1963 (Box 27)
      Item #1646
    - Unknown photographer The Mills Brothers boarding Southwest Airlines flight. Photographic postcard, 1963 (Box 27)
      Item #1647
    - Devolite Peerless "Jim 'Mudcat' Grant" strikes pose in Cincinnati uniform. Photographic postcard, circa 1940 (Box 27)
      Autographed in ink, recto.
      Item #1648
    - Beebi (?), no location "Old John Wabaskaw, Kewadin, Mich." Old man stands outdoors in hat and overcoat, smokes pipe. Photographic postcard, circa 1915 (Box 27)
      Item #1649
    - Unknown photographer Portrait of baby "Wheeler McIntosh Thackston, three weeks"; held by black nurse in uniform with apron and cap. Photographic postcard, circa 1915 (Box 27)
      Baby identified in pencil, verso.
      Item #1650
    - Unknown photographer "Negro Baptizing, Tennessee River." Baptism in river; large crowd on banks. Photographic postcard, circa 1912 (Box 27)
      Item #1651
    - Unknown photographer "I'se Got a Permit:" young boy, barefoot, stands holding stick over shallow river; fake fishing line drawn in negative. Photographic postcard, 1917 (Box 27)
      Item #1652
    - Unknown photographer Full length standing outdoor portrait of Saul Butler, of Rock Island; athlete in track and field uniform stands beside track; crowd in distant background. Photographic postcard, 1915 (Box 27)
      Identified in ink, verso, along with distances and times of win at Big Eight May 1, 1915.
      Item #1653
    - Harris Photo Postcard Co., Pittston, PA, and Arlington, NJ "Somerville, SC" elderly man in ragged clothes stands by wood pile. Photographic postcard, circa 1915 (Box 27)
      Location indicated in negative.
      Item #1654
    - W.S. Bowman The Round-Up, Pendleton, OR Black cowboy (identified verso and on information from vendor as George Fletcher) astride bucking bronco at rodeo. Photographic postcard, circa 1910 (Box 27, Folder 1054)
      In ink, verso, "George Fletcher."
      Item #1655
    - Unknown photographer Group of six individual portraits of men in WW I uniform, seated and standing. Photographic postcard, 1918 (Box 27, Folder 1054a)
      Item #1656
    - Unknown photographer Full length formal portrait of John: man stands in set with windows, wearing shaggy chaps, cowboy hat, kerchief; holding lariat in one hand, revolver(?) in the other. Photographic postcard, circa 1905 (Box 27, Folder 1055)
      Verso, "How I look now. John"
      Item #1657
    - Unknown photographer Group portrait of privates and non-commissioned officers of the 21st Connecticut Regiment, grouped before U.S. flag. Photographic postcard, circa 1905 (Box 27, Folder 1056)
      Item #1658
    - Unknown photographer Unidentified school group on steps of brick building. One black boy. Photographic postcard, circa 1920 (Box 27, Folder 1057)
      Item #2073
  - ALBUMS
    Albums consists of fourteen photograph albums. Some are family albums; others record the experiences of individuals, including that of a private in the 101st Airborn Division during the Korean War. There are partial albums of the 1920 Dartmouth football team and a New Jersey Boy Scout troop of the 1920s. One album documents the construction of the Bulkley Bridge, while another records a military parade in upstate New York. One album contains individual portraits of the officers and men of Company F, 108th United States Colored Infantry.
    - Unknown photographer Three pages from an album, consisting of five photographs of the Dartmouth football team of 1920: group photo of young men on front of a locomotive; bust length double portrait of coach and captain; view of stadium; and full length portrait of "Johnny Shelburne, Fullback 1920, A Dartmouth Hero in the Brown Game of 1920." Album 12 x 16-1/4
      Images identified by inscriptions on pages.
      Item #1659
    - Unknown photographer Group of 73 Photographic postcards of the construction of the Bulkeley Bridge, Hartford, Connecticut. Album, circa 1903-1908 (Box 27, Folder 1058-1059)
      Built 1903-1908. Originally known as the Hartford Bridge. Album also includes photos of centenary parade celebrating bridge's completion.
      Item #1660
    - Unknown photographer Two albums: First 27 photos of N.Y., N.H.& H.R.R. Co.; Second, 16 photos of centenary parade in New York. Most of the military units in the parade identified in negatives. Album, 1908 (Box 27, Folder 1060-1061)
      Item #1661
    - Unknown photographer Album of 35 snapshots of Washington, D.C. monuments and landmarks, Washington's home at Mount Vernon, and black people at work, play and at home. Various sizes up to 3-1/4 x 3-1/4. Album, 1896 (Box 27, Folder 1062)
      Small grey paper album. "Photographs Washington, 1896, July 5-15" on front cover. "E in C" monogram in lower right hand corner.
      Item #1666
    - Unknown photographer Group of 20 snapshots of a scrap yard, mounted on black album pages no cover. All are approximately 2-3/4 x 4-3/8, both orientations. Album, 1919 May (Box 27, Folder 1063)
      Item #1667
    - Unknown photographer Album of 31 snapshots of Private Charles A. Perry and friends of the 101st Airborne Division, at Camp Breckenridge and in Korea, 1951 Official army regimental, Album, 8-1/2 X 11 (Box 27, Folder 1064)
      Grey paper cover with regimental eagle insignia in color, "My Service Record, with the 101st Airborne Division."
      Item #1669
    - Various photographers, some of whom are identified. An album of 34 photographs in a fine morocco binding; pages with arched openings lined with red; various type of portraits from full length to cameos, presumably all of the same family, some being identified verso. All cabinet size. Album, circa 1890-1910 (Box 28)
      Item #1662
    - Various photographers from New Haven, Hartford and New York An album of 48 cartes de visite, tintypes, and cabinet cards of members of the Smith family of New Haven and friends; characteristic types of later 19th century portrait photos, almost all of them formal; all in a velvet covered album with nickel plated "Souvenir" on cover, and gilt lined pages. Various formats: cartes de visite, tintypes, and cabinet cards. Clasp on album bears patent date 1884, 10 x 7-3/4, circa 1870-1900 (Box 29)
      In pencil on overleaf: "Mrs. James Young.
      Item #1663
    - Various photographers, mostly from New York City and New York State An album of 60 cartes de visite, tintypes and cabinet cards in a worn velvet album with heavily embossed pages with arched openings. Album, 10 x 8, circa 1900 (Box 30)
      Includes two novelty cartes de visite by Chas. Eisenmann, NYC: "Illararo, the Egyptian, Age 19," and "[?] Zulu" Also included, clipping of an obituary notice in remembrance of the passing of Elizabeth M. wife of William H. Lester. One photo is snapshot of a church. Dated from obituary notice.
      Item #1664
    - Unknown photographer An album of 338 snapshots and a few clippings in black embossed paper cover: young man in college; with buddies; with spouse, friends and family; a few snapshots labeled, some humorously; a few hand colored. Locales: Asbury Park, NJ, Cheyney College, and Winchester, KY. Album, 7-1/4 x 10-1/2, 1916-24 (Box 31)
      Item #1668
    - Gayford & Speidel, Rock Island, IL A unique group of 30 individual portraits of officers, non-commissioned officers, and enlisted men of Company F, 108th United States Colored Infantry all but three are identified in a fine hand in ink verso, and most have comments in apparently the same, but a lighter hand, March, 1865. Cartes de visite from an album. Photographer is identified in print, verso, of all but three which are plain. (Box 32)
      Empty album. See box 35, folders 1082-1083 for portraits.
      Item #1665
    - A family album and other photographs from Norwalk, Ohio. Blue canvas album with center oval rimmed in white metal; center panel black velvet with hand stitched flowers. Perhaps from the Noble family. Listed here are the black subjects. There is in addition a group of white subjects, not listed (mounted photographs and cabinet cards). (Box 33)
      Empty album.
      Item #2173
    - Butler Photo, Post Office Block, Chatham Young lady seated on studio stone wall with large hat on knee. Carte de visite, circa 1875 (Box 34, Folder 1065)
      Item #2173 a.
    - D.L. Heath, Norwalk, OH Young man standing with left hand on newel post, wearing heavy overcoat with velvet collar. Carte de visite, circa 1870 (Box 34)
      Verso in pencil, "R.R." Blue two-cent revenue stamp.
      Item #2173 b.
    - Unknown photographer Young man standing by overstuffed chair wearing hat and fancy three piece suit and gold watch chain. Cased, tintype, sixth plate, circa 1870 (Box 34, Folder 1066)
      Item #2173 c.
    - Unknown photographer Young girl standing by fringed chair wearing ruffled dress. Cased, tintype, sixth plate, circa 1875 (Box 34)
      Item #2173 d.
    - Unknown photographer Man with moustache wearing three piece suit. Tintype, mounted in original paper case, ninth plate, circa 1870 (Box 34, Folder 1067)
      Item #2173 e.
    - Unknown photographer Man with moustache wearing jacket, shirt and tie. Tintype, mounted in original paper case, ninth plate, circa 1875 (Box 34)
      Item #2173 f.
    - Unknown photographer Young lady standing with elegant dress and white collar, her hand resting on a slender stand. Tintype, in original oval paper case, quarter plate, circa 1875 (Box 34, Folder 1068)
      Inscription in pencil verso: "Mother"
      Item #2173 g.
    - Unknown photographer Two young women seated together and very elegantly dressed. Tintype, sixth plate, circa 1875 (Box 34)
      Item #2173 h.
    - Unknown photographer Young female child standing on crude wooden bench. Long dress with very large bow at neck. Tintype, cropped corners, sixth plate, circa 1875 (Box 34, Folder 1069)
      Item #2173 i.
    - Unknown photographer Triple portrait; two women and a man, all elegantly dressed and wearing hats, set in a rustic scene with a boat oar on rocks in the foreground. Tintype, sixth plate, circa 1880 (Box 34)
      Item #2173 j.
    - Unknown photographer Triple portrait, exterior setting. Two children seated; one stands. Tintype, ninth plate, circa 1880 (Box 34, Folder 1070)
      Item #2173 k.
    - Unknown photographer Double portrait, two young ladies; woman at left seated in dark dress and matching hat; woman on right, in white dress and hat. Tintype, sixth plate, circa 1880 (Box 34)
      Item #2173 l.
    - Unknown photographer Young lady standing beside studio baluster, wearing elegant dress. Tintype, ninth plate, circa 1880 (Box 34, Folder 1071)
      Item #2173 m.
    - Gem Gallery, Mores Broth's, Norwalk, OH Bust portrait of young man wearing checked suit and white clerical collar; medal on vest. Cabinet photograph, circa 1880 (Box 34)
      Item #2173 n.
    - Baker's Art Gallery, Columbus, OH Cameo portrait of young lady wearing choker of gold beads and earrings. Cabinet photograph, circa 1880 (Box 34, Folder 1072)
      Item #2173 o.
    - Curtiss, New London, OH Elderly man standing with cane in one hand, the other resting on a spool style fireplace screen; he wears a three piece suit with a gold watch chain. Cabinet photograph, circa 1890 (Box 34)
      Item #2173 p.
    - Foster, Norwalk, OH Young girl wearing white dress with crown and floral veil; flowers in one hand, the other raised, bearing a striped wand. Cabinet photograph, circa 1885 (Box 34, Folder 1073)
      Item #2173 q.
    - Hackett, North Fairfield, OH Cameo portrait of young man with full moustache, in three piece suit with wing collar and stick pin. Cabinet photograph, circa 1890 (Box 34)
      In pencil verso: "Friends once but strangers now how about that ... it out there. Royal Smith and ..."
      Item #2173 r.
    - Unknown photographer Four ladies and one man seated on a wall near river edge. Early 20th century photograph, mounted on elaborate gray board, 3-3/4 x 4-1/2, circa 1905 (Box 34, Folder 1074)
      Item #2173 s.
    - F.D. Foster, Norwalk, OH Oval portrait of small child in plaid dress, early 20th century photograph, 3-3/4 x 1-1/2 oval, circa 1905 (Box 34, Folder 1075)
      Item #2173 t.
    - William Pinch, Cleveland, OH Oval cameo portrait of a young girl wearing white dress and gold locket, oval, 5 x 3-1/2, circa 1915 (Box 34, Folder 1076)
      Item #2173 u.
    - Unknown photographer Five snapshots, two boys and three girls, mounted. Early 20th century photograph, mounted on board. Each measures 1-1/4 square, circa 1910 (Box 34, Folder 1077)
      Item #2173 v.
    - William Pinch, Cleveland, OH Young man wearing three piece suit sits in very elaborate chair. Early 20th century photograph, 9 x 6, circa 1920 (Box 34, Folder 1078)
      "S.S. Burke in pencil verso."
      Item #2173 w.
    - Adkin Studios, Cleveland, OH Oval portrait of young baby in christening gown, seated on bearskin rug. Early 20th century photograph, 7-3/4 x 5-3/4, circa 1925 (Box 34, Folder 1079)
      Verso, "To Mother Noble, Baby Vera Mildred Noble, Taken at 3 Months. Vera Noble. uncle Jay's daughter."
      Item #2173 x.
    - The Mart, Cleveland, OH Double portrait of mother and daughter, both wearing straw hats, Photographic postcard, 5-1/2 x 3-1/2, circa 1915 (Box 34, Folder 1080)
      Item #2173 y.
    - An album consisting of late nineteenth and early twentieth century items including twenty photographs 1-1/2 x 2" mounted two to a page on black album paper, depicting various outdoor scenes. There are also the following: mounted on cardboard and approximately 3-1/2 x 5-1/2, undated (Box 35, Folder 1081)
      a."Uncle Saul with broodmare and colt"
      b. "Negroes going to church", marked Onslow" and hand tinted.
      c. "Washing Day (An Onslow scene)" "Hagar Washing"
      d. A group of young boys holding logs
      e. A man in snow with a makeshift sled
      f. A large group on both sides of railway track at back of railcar, stacks of ties.
      Item #2174
    - Gayford & Speidel, Rock Island, IL A unique group of 30 individual portraits of officers, non-commissioned officers, and enlisted men of Company F, 108th United States Colored Infantry all but three are identified in a fine hand in ink verso, and most have comments in apparently the same, but a lighter hand, March, 1865. Cartes de visite from an album. Photographer is identified in print, verso, of all but three which are plain. (Box 35, Folder 1082-1083)
      Most subjects are typical standing or seated portraits of the period; some wear caps, some not; some are armed. Three are identified in pencil in the collector's hand, two of these (of enlisted men) were acquired separately and one is a duplicate (identities supplied by vendor), the third refers to one of the figures in the one double portrait, which is of two white officers, one is Lt. Wright who assembled the album. Most bear either a two cent orange, or a three cent green revenue stamp. The album is heavily embossed morocco, with arched openings and gold decorative lines; each slot is identified as to the soldier whose photograph was mounted in it, thus identifying the entire unit including those who's photographs are missing.